A Guide to the Paul C. Nagel Papers, n.d.
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Series VI-Correspondence
  - Subseries A--Restricted Correspondence
    - Correspondence--Stratford Hall Project 1985 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Thorpe, Maner L. (Causten manuscript) 1992-1993 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Truman Project (January-August) 1985 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--University of Missouri Press 1977-1991 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Virginia Seminary 1982 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Virginia State Library and Archives (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Western Historical Association 1986 (Box N)
    - Correspondence--Zimmer, Ann, n.d. 1989 (Box N)
    - Adams Academy paper by H. Hobart Holly (Box O)
    - Adams Lectures--Miscellaneous (Box O)
    - Adams Lectures--Miscellaneous in Virginia 1984-1987 (Box O)
    - Colonial Dames of America Lecture 11 March 1982 (Box o)
    - JFK Library Lecture Correspondence, n.d. (Box O)
    - Jamestown Society Lecture 13 November 1982 (Box O)
    - Lee Birthday Talk (Box O)
    - Lecture programs for Old House, n.d. (Box O)
    - Nabby Lecture (Abigail Adams Smith), n.d. (Box O)
    - Quincy Historical Society Lectures 1983, 1986 (Box O)
    - Sister Lon Adams Lecture draft, n.d. (Box O)
    - Three Sisters from Medford, Three Sisters from Weymouth 1986 (Box O)
    - University of Georgia Lecture 29 March 1984 (Box O)
    - Virginia Historical Society Annual Address (January) 1981 (Box O)
    - Publications (Box O)
- Series VII--Adams Women
  - Adams Women--Manuscripts (1 of 5) (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Adams Women--Manuscripts (2 of 5) (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Adams Women--Manuscripts (3 of 5) (Box-folder 21.6)
  - Adams Women-Manuscripts (4 of 5) (Box-folder 21.7)
  - Adams Women-Manuscripts (5 of 5) (Box-folder 21.8)
  - Adams Women-Manuscript Index (Box-folder 21.9)
  - Adams Women-Proof (1 of 5) (Box-folder 21.10)
  - Adams Women--Proof (2 of 5) (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Adams Women-Proof (3 of 5) (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Adams Women-Proof (4 of 5) (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Adams Women-Proof (5 of 5) (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Adams Women-Second Proof (1 of 5) (Box-folder 22.5)
  - Adams Women-Second Proof (2 of 5) (Box-folder 22.6)
  - Adams Women--Second Proof (3 of 5) (Box-folder 22.7)
  - Adams Women-Second Proof (4 of 5) (Box-folder 22.8)
  - Adams Women-Second Proof (5 of 5) (Box-folder 22.9)
  - Adams Women Discard (Box-folder 22.10)
  - Adams Women Clippings (Box-folder 22.11)
  - Adams Women Correspondence 1983-1987 (Box-folder 22.12)
  - Adams Women Correspondence (Personal) (Box-folder 23.1)
  - Adams Women Permissions (Box-folder 23.2)
  - Adams Women Xeroxes (Box-folder 23.3)
  - Descriptions for Illustrations (Box-folder 23.4)
  - Lecture-Adams National Historic Site 1977 (Box-folder 23.5)
  - Lecture- Crypt (Box-folder 23.6)
  - Lecture-John Quincy Adams II (Box-folder 23.7)
  - Lecture-Old House Talks (Box-folder 23.8)
  - Lecture--Old House Talks 1985 (Box-folder 23.9)
  - Lecture--Old House Talks 1987 (Box-folder 23.10)
  - Louisa (Box-folder 23.11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box-folder 23.12)
  - Nabby (Box-folder 23.13)
  - Sister Lou (early material) (Box-folder 24.1)
  - Three Sisters from Weymouth (Box-folder 24.2)
  - Early Notes (Box-folder 24.3)
  - Firsts-Drafts Early Chapters (1 of 4) (Box-folder 24.4)
  - First Drafts--Early Chapters (2 of 4) (Box-folder 24.5)
  - First Drafts--Early Chapters (3 of 4) (Box-folder 24.6)
  - First Drafts--Early Chapters (4 of 4) (Box-folder 24.7)
  - Draft Folder (1 of 5) (Box-folder 24.8)
  - Draft (2 of 5) (Box-folder 24.9)
  - Draft (3 of 5) (Box-folder 25.1)
  - Draft (4 of 5) (Box-folder 25.2)
  - Draft (5 of 5) (Box-folder 25.3)
  - Discard from Reprints (Box-folder 25.4)
- Series VIII--George Caleb Bingham
  Manuscript sources were used in Salt Lake City in March 1988 in the creation of this essay.
  - George Caleb Bingham--Early Drafts I (Box-folder 25.5)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Early Drafts II (Box-folder 25.6)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Draft (Box-folder 25.7)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Final Draft (Box-folder 25.8)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Manuscripts Sources (1 of 4) (Box-folder 25.9)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Manuscript Sources (2 of 4) (Box-folder 26.1)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Manuscript Sources (3 of 4) (Box-folder 26.2)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Manuscripts Sources (4 of 4) (Box-folder 26.3)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Additional Mss Sources (1 of 3) (Box-folder 26.4)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Additional Mss Sources (2 of 3) (Box-folder 26.5)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Additional Mss Sources (3 of 3) (Box-folder 26.6)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Related Materials (1 of 5) (Box-folder 27.1)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Related Materials (2 of 5) (Box-folder 27.2)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Related Materials (3 of 5) (Box-folder 27.3)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Related Materials (4 of 5) (Box-folder 27.4)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Related Materials (5 of 5) (Box-folder 27.5)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Completed Manuscript (1 of 2) (Box-folder 27.6)
  - George Caleb Bingham--Completed Manuscript (2 of 2) (Box-folder 27.7)
- Series IX--Lee Book
  - Lee Book Correspondence 1990 (Box-folder 28.1)
  - Lee Book Correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 28.2)
  - Copy of The Lees of Virginia by Nagel (Box-folder 28.3)